<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Considerations humbly offer'd to the Honourable House of Commons, by the planters, and others, trading to our British plantations, in relation to the African Company's petition, now before this Honourable House</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1698</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A80363</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C5909CA</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R231635</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99899868</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99899868</idno>
            <idno type="VID">170791</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A80363)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 170791)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2462:13)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Considerations humbly offer'd to the Honourable House of Commons, by the planters, and others, trading to our British plantations, in relation to the African Company's petition, now before this Honourable House</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1698?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Date of publication from Wing CD-ROM, 1996.</note>
                  <note>With a docket title.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Folger Shakespeare Library, Washington, D.C.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Royal African Company --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Trade regulation --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Commerce --  Africa --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>Paul Schaffner</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>Paul Schaffner</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="petition">
            <pb facs="tcp:170791:1"/>
            <head>CONSIDERATIONS Humbly Offer'd To the Honourable <hi>HOUSE of COMMONS,</hi> BY THE Planters, and Others, trading to our <hi>Britiſh</hi> Plantations, in Relation to the <hi>African</hi> Company's Petition, now before this Honourable HOUSE.</head>
            <p>THAT it being of ſo great Importance to this Nation to encourage and ſupport the Plantations, it will be of abſolute Neceſſity to have them plentifully ſupply'd with Negroes, by whoſe Labour all the Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dities of thoſe Countries are produc'd; which Production is all clear Gains to this Nation, and better than the Mines of Gold and Silver are to the <hi>Spa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niards;</hi> which can never be throughly done otherwiſe, than by a free open Trade, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out being confin'd to the narrow Compaſs of a few People, in a ſmall Joint-Stock.</p>
            <p>There is not a Negro but produceth as much Commodity, either Sugar, Indigo, Tobacco, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as will load one Tun of Shipping; the Increaſe of which Produce will alſo largely increaſe the Conſumption of the Woollen, and other <hi>Britiſh</hi> Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factures, and augment the Revenues of the Crown.</p>
            <p>A great Quantity of the Product of our Plantation-Commodities will enable the <hi>Britiſh</hi> Merchants to make large Exportations to foreign Markets, and put them into a Capacity to under-ſell all other Nations, that vie with us in the ſame Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities; which will not only diſcourage their Plantations, but greatly encourage our own.</p>
            <p>Since the <hi>African</hi> Company do ſet forth in their Petition, That by their Charge in maintaining their Forts and Caſtles, in ſecuring that Trade on the Coaſt of <hi>Africa,</hi> the Weſtern Plantations have been furniſhed with Negroes; we the Planters do ſay, That we have paid a Duty of 10 <hi>per Cent.</hi> for the ſame, and that had it not been more for the Separate Traders than the <hi>African</hi> Company, ſince the opening of the ſaid Trade by the late Act of Parliament, the Plantations had been but poor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſerved; for by Experience, we have found much greater Numbers of Negroes brought to our Plantations, than ever were during the time of the ſaid <hi>African</hi> Company's having that Trade in their own Hands, excluſive of all others.</p>
            <p>Therefore ſince the Plantations have receiv'd a more viſible Advantage from the <hi>African</hi> Trade, by having greater Quantities of Negroes brought among them by the Separate Traders, ſince the ſaid Trade has been laid open, than ever were be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore: And as the Product of our Iſlands are largely increas'd thereby, we are hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly of Opinion, that the Intereſt of the Plantations is of infinitely greater Concern to be preſerved, than any Company with a Joint-Stock can pretend to.</p>
            <p rend="italic">Wherefore we hope, That the Honourable <hi>Houſe of Commons</hi> will free us from the heavy Burden of the Duty of <hi>10 per Cent.</hi> which we conceive muſt be advanced on the Price of Negroes; and that the ſaid <hi>African</hi> Trade may be continu'd free and open to all People that deſire to trade thither, under ſuch Regulations as the Trade to <hi>Turky,</hi> or as ſhall be thought fit.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="docket_title">
            <pb facs="tcp:170791:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>CONSIDERATIONS Humbly offer'd by the Planters, and Others, trading to our <hi>Britiſh</hi> Plantations, In Relation to the <hi>AFRICAN</hi> Company's PETITION.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
